Duncan White Nottingham 07776 135997 <u>duncanwhite.co.uk</u> <u>github.com/duncan-s-white</u> <u>duncanstanleywhite@gmail.com</u>

I am a developer from Nottingham with experience of front end and back end technologies. I have just completed a 13 week skills bootcamp run by Northcoders, which I chose to do due to its content, practical nature and the opportunity to collaborate with others.

Through taking this course I have been successful in my goal to expand my knowledge of Javascript, test driven development and front end tools such as React.

Leading up to the course I was using online learning resources and working on small projects in order to advance my professional development.

This recent exposure to the technology industry has built on my existing experience which started with my studies and continued during my time working in and running an E-commerce retail business with my brothers.

Technical Skills

Languages: Javascript, PHP, SQL

Front End: React, Material UI, HTML5, CSS, JQuery, Bootstrap

Back End: PSQL, MySQL, Express, NodeJS

Testing: Jest, Supertest

Experience

Northcoders - full stack software developer bootcamp

This course has enabled me to update and expand my understanding of industry standards and tools, such as Jest for test driven development and git / GitHub for collaboration and version control.

I enjoyed the regular paired projects with numerous course participants, in which I was able to demonstrate adaptive team working in response to a variety of challenges.

Personal Portfolio: https://duncanwhite.co.uk

Front End Project: React and MaterialUI front end to the API

Hosted: https://dw-nc-news.netlify.app/

GitHub: https://github.com/duncan-s-white/fe-nc-news

Back End Project: A RESTful API server, developed with Node and Express

Hosted: https://dw-nc-news.herokuapp.com/api

GitHub: https://github.com/duncan-s-white/news-api

Final Project: Pingo, a photo bingo game. React Native and Firebase mobile app.

GitHub: https://github.com/baddis01/Pingo-Final-Project

Trustee for Access Adventures (2019-Present)

In 2019 I was co-opted as a trustee for the British Disabled Waterski & Wakeboard Association during their merger with Access Adventures.

Since then I have worked with the CEO of the charity to research and setup a Constituent Relationship Management system (CiviCRM) which I administer. This automates several repetitive processes and manages the storage and maintenance of the charity's data.

Director for Electro Supplies Ltd (2010-2019)

This was a business that I owned and ran with my two brothers.

It was an E-commerce business which took in excess of £12 million worth of orders through the website during my time with the company.

My main roles were to maintain and develop the e-commerce website and administration. Some notable achievements and responsibilities were:

- Launch of e-commerce software, a customised version of OSCommerce. This
 involved extensive alterations to the administration using PHP, JQuery and CSS
 Bootstrap to fulfil the operational and business needs of the company including:
 - Installing and modifying OSCommerce add-ons, to increase functionality.
 - Developing a custom quoting system by extending and modifying the existing code and database from the orders part of the system.
 - Adding Ajax features to give a smoother user experience.
 - Theming with CSS bootstrap to improve usability and responsiveness.
- Writing PHP code to reduce repetitive staff jobs, such as processing spreadsheets.
- Participating in regular meetings, to discuss the aims and direction of the company.

Education

Southampton Solent University (2006-2008)

Completed 6 Modules for BA - Internet Applications Development

City & Islington College (2004-2005)

Access to Digital Media

Harlow Itec (2002)

European Computer Driving Licence

City & Guilds IT Diploma in Computer Applications (A Level 2 Vocational Qualification)

St. Mary's Catholic School, Bishop's Stortford, AS Levels (2000-2001)

Mathematics, Religious Studies, Biology

GCSE's (1995-2000)

10 x GCSE A* - B